thepeninsulaqatar.com 2019-11-12

# The Peninsula Qatar - Privacy Site - The Peninsula Qatar

The Peninsula Newspaper, a part of Dar Al Sharq Group, operates the www.thepeninsulaqatar.com website.

This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our website.

We use your data to provide and improve the website experience. By using the website, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy. 

#### **Personal Data**

We do not collect personal data like name, email or address of the user. Some of the third party services we use like disqus or the job portal on our website might collect your personal data. In this regard, please check the individual service provider’s privacy policy.

The Peninsula will not ask for your personal details unless you contact us from your side for any queries.

Cookies and Usage Data

#### **Usage Data**

We may collect information how our website is accessed and used ("Usage Data"). This Usage Data may include information such as your computer's Internet Protocol address (e.g. IP address), browser type, browser version, the pages of our website that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data. These are Anonymous Data and cant be used to identify the user.

#### **Tracking & Cookies Data**

We use cookies and similar tracking technologies to track the activity on our advertisements and hold certain information.

Cookies are files with small amount of data which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device. 

Your information may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction.

If you are located outside Qatar and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the data to Qatar and process it there.

Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer.

## **Disclosure Of Data**

The Peninsula may disclose your Personal Data in good faith that such action is necessary to: To comply with a legal obligation, to protect and defend the rights or property of The Peninsula and to prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the wesite.

## **Service Providers**

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our website.

### **Analytics**

We may use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyze the use of our Service.

****Google Analytics****

Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Service available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity.

For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page: [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en)

Google Ads

Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to our website or other websites.

Google's use of advertising cookies enables it and its partners to serve ads to users based on their visit to sites and/or other sites on the Internet.

Users may opt out of personalized advertising by visiting Ads Settings. (Alternatively, you can opt out of personalized advertising by visiting www.aboutads.info.)

## **Links To Other Sites**

Our website sometimes contain links to other websites whose privacy policies may be different to ours. Visitors should consult the other sites’ privacy notices as we have no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by, these third parties.

We also use reputable third party to serve the advertisements that you see on our pages. In the course of serving advertisements, our third-party advertiser may place or recognise a unique “cookie” on your browser and may use information (not including your name, address, e-mail address) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

Our website has links to other website(s). The privacy policies of these website(s) is not under our control. Once you leave our servers, use of any information you provide is governed by the privacy policy of the operator of the site you are visiting. It is advisable to read their privacy policies for further information.

## **Changes To This Privacy Policy**

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

## **Contact Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us by email: [pr@pen.com.qa](mailto:pr@pen.com.qa)
